<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Beta Thoughts</title>
    <link>http://pnarula.com/tags/google&#43;/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Beta Thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://pnarula.com/tags/google&#43;/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Bay area at its best Thanks to Bjorn Goerke</title>
      <link>http://pnarula.com/2013/bay-area-at-its-best-thanks-to-bjorn-goerke/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 22:09:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pnarula.com/2013/bay-area-at-its-best-thanks-to-bjorn-goerke/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bay area at its best. Thanks to Bjorn Goerke for quoting this by Steinbeck which is so apt ( &lt;a href=&#34;http://bgoerke.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/ive-never-seen-her-more-lovely/&#34; onclick=&#34;_gaq.push([&#39;_trackEvent&#39;, &#39;outbound-article&#39;, &#39;http://bgoerke.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/ive-never-seen-her-more-lovely/&#39;, &#39;http://bgoerke.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/ive-never-seen-her-more-lovely/&#39;]);&#34;  class=&#34;ot-anchor&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bgoerke.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/ive-never-seen-her-more-lovely/&#34;&gt;http://bgoerke.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/ive-never-seen-her-more-lovely/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was a child growing up in Salinas we called San Francisco “the City”. Of course it was the only city we knew, but I still think of it as the City, and so does everyone else who has ever associated with it. A strange and exclusive word is “city”. Besides San Francisco, only small sections of London and Rome stay in the mind as the City. New Yorkers say they go to town. Paris has no title but Paris. Mexico City is the Capital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;San Francisco put on a show for me. I saw her across the bay, from the great road that bypasses Sausalito and enters the Golden Gate Bridge. The afternoon sun painted her white and gold rising on her hills like a noble city in a happy dream. A city on hills has it over flatland places. New York makes its own hills with craning buildings, but this gold and white acropolis rising wave on wave against the blue of the Pacific sky was a stunning thing, a painted thing like a picture of a medieval Italian city which can never have existed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stopped in a parking place to look at her and the necklace bridge over the entrance from the sea that led to her. Over the green higher hills to the south, the evening fog rolled like herds of sheep coming to cote in the golden city. I’ve never seen her more lovely. When I was a child and we were going to the City, I couldn’t sleep for several nights before, out of bursting excitement. She leaves a mark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FROM John Steinbeck, Travels with Charley, 1962&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I have been slowly reading Thinking fast</title>
      <link>http://pnarula.com/2012/i-have-been-slowly-reading-thinking-fast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 06:06:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pnarula.com/2012/i-have-been-slowly-reading-thinking-fast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been slowly reading ”Thinking fast and slow” by Daniel Kahneman. It is full of fun phrases like ” nonregressive assessment of weak evidence” still it is an important book in understanding of human biases and how we decide what we decide. I am sure toread it multiple times. One really good thing is you can pick any chapter and read it a they are independent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BYO or otherwise Breaking the 10000 server</title>
      <link>http://pnarula.com/2011/byo-or-otherwise-breaking-the-10000-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2011 02:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pnarula.com/2011/byo-or-otherwise-breaking-the-10000-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BYO or otherwise &amp;#8211; Breaking the 10000 server barrier via Gigaom&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s in that 5 to 7.5MW area where the company starts having to know about the niceties of chillers and power systems, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When you break through the 10,000 server barrier — that’s when you start needing 3 to 5MW of power and now you’re getting into major facility costs where you have to have multiple diesel generators, and complex power and cooling systems. And it’s in that 10,000 to 100,000 server zone where costs soar. At that point, there aren’t many companies on the planet that can achieve the scale of an Amazon, a Rackspace, a Google, or a Microsoft. So why not trust your loads to the experts?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gigaom.com/cloud/do-byo-data-centers-make-sense-anymore&#34; onclick=&#34;_gaq.push([&#39;_trackEvent&#39;, &#39;outbound-article&#39;, &#39;http://gigaom.com/cloud/do-byo-data-centers-make-sense-anymore&#39;, &#39;Do BYO data centers make sense anymore?&#39;]);&#34; &gt;Do BYO data centers make sense anymore?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://images0-focus-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?container=focus&amp;gadget=a&amp;resize_h=100&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fgigaom2.files.wordpress.com%2F2011%2F12%2F2754478731_6cac6d30a8_z-e1323205331315.jpg%3Fw%3D476&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; /&gt;In this era of cheap-and-reliable renta-data centers run by Amazon, Rackspace, and others, does it make sense for a company to build a new data center on it&amp;rsquo;s own? Unsurprisingly, Amazon&amp;rsquo;s own James H&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards more lighted pixels It has been</title>
      <link>http://pnarula.com/2011/towards-more-lighted-pixels-it-has-been/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2011 19:43:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pnarula.com/2011/towards-more-lighted-pixels-it-has-been/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Towards more lighted pixels&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been more than three years that I have had a DSLR(T1i) My usage has been mostly family outings with friends and family. But only after these years of use I have come to terms with most of the controls in the camera except for flash. Last night we were at global wonder winterland (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.globalwonderland.org/2011/&#34; onclick=&#34;_gaq.push([&#39;_trackEvent&#39;, &#39;outbound-article&#39;, &#39;http://www.globalwonderland.org/2011/&#39;, &#39;http://www.globalwonderland.org/2011/&#39;]);&#34; &gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.globalwonderland.org/2011/&#34;&gt;http://www.globalwonderland.org/2011/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) where I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to think about setting to change and it came naturally. Still there was one instance where I was in hurry and I used the short cut to Auto  &lt;img src=&#34;http://pnarula.com/wp/wp-includes/images/smilies/simple-smile.png&#34; alt=&#34;:)&#34; class=&#34;wp-smiley&#34; style=&#34;height: 1em; max-height: 1em;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another interesting thing that I have been noticing is the trend of everyone moving to DSLRs. At the global wonder winterland one could see more DSLRs and less P&amp;amp;Ses Ofcourse there were our iPhone photographers too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.10150434292678121.367985.734243120&amp;#038;type=1&amp;#038;l=b70cb2d0e3&#34; onclick=&#34;_gaq.push([&#39;_trackEvent&#39;, &#39;outbound-article&#39;, &#39;https://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.10150434292678121.367985.734243120&amp;#038;type=1&amp;#038;l=b70cb2d0e3&#39;, &#39;Global Wonder Winterland | Facebook&#39;]);&#34; &gt;Global Wonder Winterland | Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digitopoly is becoming my favorite blog</title>
      <link>http://pnarula.com/2011/digitopoly-is-becoming-my-favorite-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2011 06:36:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pnarula.com/2011/digitopoly-is-becoming-my-favorite-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Digitopoly is becoming my favorite blog as they seem to touch the very topics I am interested in. Future of libraries and books is something I think often. Let us say everytime I visit the local library. Here is there thinking on why reading book should be more like going to cinema rather than owning a physical artifact. You can always argue that there are folks who like to own discs/tapes but that would be minority compared to folks who see the movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Here is the central fact about book publishing: lending is the natural state. Authors produce a book that is improved by others (including editors etc). Then people read the book and that is where it has primary value. Notice that there is no ‘then people buy the book’ stage in the middle or ‘then people place the book on their shelves forever more’ after these. Those are things people did because (a) they had to buy a physical copy and (b) they got used to keeping the physical copy. But for libraries, none of that was relevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue book publishers face — and so many have said it I really shouldn’t bother, but I will — is that they are wedded to a strategy whereby they sell owned copies rather than reading. That model did translate over to eBooks and, in many respects, eBooks are actually harder to share as owned copies than physical books. Amazon and others have tried to break those constraints but it is safe to say that sharing is hard. Although, when you have a family account things become simpler. But institutionalised lending of eBooks may be very attractive to readers.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digitopoly.org/2011/11/28/lending-is-the-right-model&#34; onclick=&#34;_gaq.push([&#39;_trackEvent&#39;, &#39;outbound-article&#39;, &#39;http://www.digitopoly.org/2011/11/28/lending-is-the-right-model&#39;, &#39;Lending is the right model | Digitopoly&#39;]);&#34; &gt;Lending is the right model | Digitopoly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft&#34; src=&#34;http://images0-focus-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?container=focus&amp;gadget=a&amp;resize_h=100&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.digitopoly.org%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2011%2F11%2F4511652432_d443eddfe6-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;Digitopoly. About; Authors. Erik Brynjolfsson; Joshua Gans; Shane Greenstein. Posts by Author. Erik Brynjolfsson; Joshua Gans; Shane Greenstein. Blog Network. Core Economics; Economics of Information;&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me Myself and Big Data It seems the future</title>
      <link>http://pnarula.com/2011/me-myself-and-big-data-it-seems-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2011 06:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pnarula.com/2011/me-myself-and-big-data-it-seems-the-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Me Myself and Big Data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems the future for self big data is not very far and I think it would be a good thing. Few days ago I read about Up from Jawbone (&lt;a href=&#34;http://jawbone.com/up&#34; onclick=&#34;_gaq.push([&#39;_trackEvent&#39;, &#39;outbound-article&#39;, &#39;http://jawbone.com/up&#39;, &#39;http://jawbone.com/up&#39;]);&#34; &gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jawbone.com/up&#34;&gt;http://jawbone.com/up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) which tracks activity data you in the hope it would nudge you for healthier style. But Larry Smarr from UCSD, chronicles&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quantified Health:&lt;br /&gt;
Towards Digitally Enabled Genomic Medicine:A 10-Year Detective Story of Quantifying My Body (Link below)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amount of data collected as part of this detective work is truly amazing. I am sure it must have required a lot of effort and motivation to do this over 10 years. This required effort to collect self bio markers over long periods would definitely decrease in future with more and more things like Up resulting in insights that were unthinkable earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stratnews.com/recentissues.php?mode=show&amp;#038;issue=2011-09-29&#34; onclick=&#34;_gaq.push([&#39;_trackEvent&#39;, &#39;outbound-article&#39;, &#39;http://www.stratnews.com/recentissues.php?mode=show&amp;#038;issue=2011-09-29&#39;, &#39;Strategic News Service &amp;#8211; Recent IssuesSTRATEGIC NEWS SERVICE&#39;]);&#34; &gt;Strategic News Service &amp;#8211; Recent IssuesSTRATEGIC NEWS SERVICE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://images0-focus-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?container=focus&amp;#038;gadget=a&amp;#038;resize_h=100&amp;#038;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.stratnews.com%2Fimages%2Fthird_1.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; /&gt;In This Issue. Feature: Special Letter: Quantified Health: A 10-Year Detective Story. of Digitally Enabled Genomic Medicine. Nutrition, Exercise, and Sleep: The Foundations for a. Healthier Self. Your&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trouble with bright kids There is very good</title>
      <link>http://pnarula.com/2011/trouble-with-bright-kids-there-is-very-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2011 06:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pnarula.com/2011/trouble-with-bright-kids-there-is-very-good/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Trouble with bright kids&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is very good discussion going at Hacker News (&lt;a href=&#34;http://news.ycombinator.org/item?id=3284169&#34; onclick=&#34;_gaq.push([&#39;_trackEvent&#39;, &#39;outbound-article&#39;, &#39;http://news.ycombinator.org/item?id=3284169&#39;, &#39;http://news.ycombinator.org/item?id=3284169&#39;]);&#34; &gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://news.ycombinator.org/item?id=3284169&#34;&gt;http://news.ycombinator.org/item?id=3284169&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) on an HBR blogs article. TL;DR version is that bright kids get praised for smartness plus our education system works for the lowest common denominator which means less challenges for the bright ones. These two things work against the bright kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.hbr.org/cs/2011/11/the_trouble_with_bright_kids.html?cm_sp=most_widget-_-default-_-The+Trouble+With+Bright+Kids&#34; onclick=&#34;_gaq.push([&#39;_trackEvent&#39;, &#39;outbound-article&#39;, &#39;http://blogs.hbr.org/cs/2011/11/the_trouble_with_bright_kids.html?cm_sp=most_widget-_-default-_-The+Trouble+With+Bright+Kids&#39;, &#39;The Trouble With Bright Kids &amp;#8211; Heidi Grant Halvorson &amp;#8211; Harvard Business Review&#39;]);&#34; &gt;The Trouble With Bright Kids &amp;#8211; Heidi Grant Halvorson &amp;#8211; Harvard Business Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://images0-focus-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?container=focus&amp;#038;gadget=a&amp;#038;resize_h=100&amp;#038;url=http%3A%2F%2Fhbr.org%2Fhbrg-main%2Fresources%2Fimages%2Ffavicon_64.png&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; /&gt;Business bloggers at Harvard Business Review discuss a variety of business topics including managing people, innovation, leadership, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photography is an art Dance photography</title>
      <link>http://pnarula.com/2011/photography-is-an-art-dance-photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2011 16:56:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pnarula.com/2011/photography-is-an-art-dance-photography/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Photography is an art. Dance photography is an extreme form of it due to low light conditions, fast moving objects etc. Peter Norvig, a legendary programmers shares his thoughts on Dance Photography in a really good tutorial form. Read and learn (Most of the indoor parties are simpler examples of dance photography&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://norvig.com/dance-photography.html&#34; onclick=&#34;_gaq.push([&#39;_trackEvent&#39;, &#39;outbound-article&#39;, &#39;http://norvig.com/dance-photography.html&#39;, &#39;Dance Photography&#39;]);&#34; &gt;Dance Photography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://images0-focus-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?container=focus&amp;gadget=a&amp;resize_h=100&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fpn.smugmug.com%2FDance%2FDance-Photography%2Fi-pPnNBQx%2F1%2FS%2FIMG9476-S.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; /&gt;Table of Contents 1: Initial Disappointment 2: Basic Photo Editing 3: Basic Equipment 4: Types of Blur 5: Subject Motion Blur 6: Camera Shake 7: Plane of Focus and Depth of Field 8: Noise 9: Exposure &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A colored e reader This is sweet</title>
      <link>http://pnarula.com/2011/a-colored-e-reader-this-is-sweet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 05:19:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pnarula.com/2011/a-colored-e-reader-this-is-sweet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A colored e-reader. This is sweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;embed-youtube&#39; style=&#39;text-align:center; display: block;&#39;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happened to read a bit of silicon valley</title>
      <link>http://pnarula.com/2011/happened-to-read-a-bit-of-silicon-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2011 07:11:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pnarula.com/2011/happened-to-read-a-bit-of-silicon-valley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happened to read a bit of silicon valley history from couple of sources recently. One recurring theme is as follows (this bit is from What the Dormouse Said)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;but before long he was bored with building xxxxx that required little of his creativity, and he began looking for something more interesting to work on&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When thinking about giants of computing</title>
      <link>http://pnarula.com/2011/when-thinking-about-giants-of-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2011 21:57:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pnarula.com/2011/when-thinking-about-giants-of-computing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When thinking about giants of computing one easily forgets that they were young once, this tidbit from What the Dormouse Said about Doug Engelbart is very interesting. His manager is complaining about him to his manager&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jerry, I know you well enough. I have two things to say, and it will only take sixty seconds point number one is that you have to choose.you either have to risk it on this guy our you have to fire him the second thing I have to say its that this the brightest guy I have ever worked with.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Very tough story to read It is just terrifying</title>
      <link>http://pnarula.com/2011/very-tough-story-to-read-it-is-just-terrifying/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2011 02:25:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pnarula.com/2011/very-tough-story-to-read-it-is-just-terrifying/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Very tough story to read. It is just terrifying to know that there are millions of girls who are pushed into this every year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2011/11/17/opinion/kristof-the-face-of-modern-slavery.html?_r=1&amp;hp&#34; onclick=&#34;_gaq.push([&#39;_trackEvent&#39;, &#39;outbound-article&#39;, &#39;http://www.nytimes.com/2011/11/17/opinion/kristof-the-face-of-modern-slavery.html?_r=1&amp;hp&#39;, &#39;The Face of Modern Slavery&#39;]);&#34; &gt;The Face of Modern Slavery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://images0-focus-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?container=focus&amp;gadget=a&amp;resize_h=100&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fgraphics8.nytimes.com%2Fimages%2F2011%2F11%2F17%2Fopinion%2F17KRISTOF%2F17KRISTOF-articleInline.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; /&gt;When 6-year-olds are sold to be tortured and raped, it’s time for a 21st-century abolitionist movement to end human trafficking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lumia 800 looks good</title>
      <link>http://pnarula.com/2011/lumia-800-looks-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2011 01:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pnarula.com/2011/lumia-800-looks-good/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lumia 800 looks good&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has been a lot of noise about this new phone from Nokia called Lumia 800. Finally got a chance to read up on it. Following the cues of its earlier buddy N9, Lumia 800 looks very good. Let us see how it goes in the world with MS Mango.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pcworld.com/article/244187/nokia_lumia_800_review_nokias_most_promising_smartphone_yet.html&#34; onclick=&#34;_gaq.push([&#39;_trackEvent&#39;, &#39;outbound-article&#39;, &#39;http://www.pcworld.com/article/244187/nokia_lumia_800_review_nokias_most_promising_smartphone_yet.html&#39;, &#39;Nokia Lumia 800 Phone Review&#39;]);&#34; &gt;Nokia Lumia 800 Phone Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft&#34; src=&#34;http://images0-focus-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?container=focus&amp;gadget=a&amp;resize_h=100&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fzapp1.staticworld.net%2Freviews%2Fgraphics%2Fproducts%2Fuploaded%2Fnokia_lumia_800_1163591_g1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;Nokia&amp;#8217;s first Windows Phone has a great design and performs solidly, but the Lumia 800 lacks a few perks its competitors flaunt&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For the stat lovers in you This is actually pretty good and can be used for a lot</title>
      <link>http://pnarula.com/2011/for-the-stat-lovers-in-you-this-is-actually-pretty-good-and-can-be-used-for-a-lot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 21:29:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pnarula.com/2011/for-the-stat-lovers-in-you-this-is-actually-pretty-good-and-can-be-used-for-a-lot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the stat lovers in you. This is actually pretty good and can be used for a lot of other scenarios&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jeffreybreen.wordpress.com/2011/07/04/twitter-text-mining-r-slides/&#34; onclick=&#34;_gaq.push([&#39;_trackEvent&#39;, &#39;outbound-article&#39;, &#39;http://jeffreybreen.wordpress.com/2011/07/04/twitter-text-mining-r-slides/&#39;, &#39;slides from my R tutorial on Twitter text mining #rstats « Things &amp;#8230;&#39;]);&#34; &gt;slides from my R tutorial on Twitter text mining #rstats « Things &lt;b&gt;&amp;#8230;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags. 24 altitude autocomplete BlackBerry Bluetooth Boston Cisco cloud computing Dell DNS email ESX Firefox Fox Geocoding ggobi ggplot2 GIS Google Maps hack hardware linux Mac mapping MySQL nightlight&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hat tip to Nikhil for recommending this</title>
      <link>http://pnarula.com/2011/hat-tip-to-nikhil-for-recommending-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 19:57:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pnarula.com/2011/hat-tip-to-nikhil-for-recommending-this/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hat tip to Nikhil for recommending this article &lt;a href=&#34;http://hbswk.hbs.edu/rss/6752.html&#34; onclick=&#34;_gaq.push([&#39;_trackEvent&#39;, &#39;outbound-article&#39;, &#39;http://hbswk.hbs.edu/rss/6752.html&#39;, &#39;http://hbswk.hbs.edu/rss/6752.html&#39;]);&#34; &gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://hbswk.hbs.edu/rss/6752.html&#34;&gt;http://hbswk.hbs.edu/rss/6752.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img src=&#34;http://images0-focus-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?container=focus&amp;#038;gadget=a&amp;#038;resize_h=100&amp;#038;url=http%3A%2F%2Fhbswk.hbs.edu%2Fimages%2Fsite%2Fsix.level.2.gif&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; /&gt;]()&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>